HARPRIT SINGH

Sales & Marketing

WORK EXPERIENCE (Total 20+ Years)



ABOUT ME

Results-driven and motivated Sales professional with more then 20+ years of work experience in various domains - IT & Softwares, Digital, Learning & Development, Banking, Insurance, FMCD, Branding, Advertisement, Creative.

Experience in driving revenue, managing relationships, collaborating with sales leaders & C Level executives. Known for having excelent time management, leadership, communication & customer handling skills & ability to formulate marketing strategies.

Ready to develop new opportunities with growth potential, ready to develop negotiating strategies & integrate new venture with company strategy.

WORK EXPERIENCE -

Goalseek Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Software & Technology Solutions | Corporate Learning & Development June 2022 - Present

Head - Sales & Marketing Location - Mumbai

Entrepreneurial Venture

Jan 2012 - March 2022

Entrepreneur sinch 2012 engaged mostly with SME & Corporates for :

Software Development & Sales - Developed SAAS, ERP, HRM, Loyalty softwares and sold in Various parts of India. Custom development for corporates like Tata group, Dabur, Khadim, Bata & Govt. of Jharkhand, Odissa. International Clients in Kenya, Australia, Canada.

Creative & Branding, Advertising & PR - Professionaly created a venture to cater SME, Corporate & Large Retail clients.

Website Developemnt & Digital Marketing - Created Good exposure with quality website designes & ecommerce development. Effective Digital marketing services for both India & International Clients.

HDFC Bank Ltd - Sales Manager (Direct, Indirect & Channel)

Retail Assets, Branch Banking, Forex November 2007 - November 2011 | Jharkhand & Odissa

Bajaj Allianze Life Isurance Ltd. - Sales Manager

Life Insurance - Agency Channel Feb 2007 - August 2007 | Jamshedpur

ICICI Bank Ltd - Business Channel Manager

Retail Assets - Loans March 2004 - Jan 2007 | Jamshedpur

Eureka Forbes - Sales Executive

Direct Sales - Vaccum Cleaner & Aquaguard August 2003 - Feb 2004 | Jamshedpur

Detail Work Experience -

Goalseek Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Software & Technology Solutions | Corporate Learning & Development Solution

Head - Sales & Marketing August 2023 - Present | Mumbai

Manager - Business Development June 2022 - July 2023 | Mumbai

- Working as Head of Sales & Marketing.
- Responsible for building network & relationship, strategic partnership with existing Key Clients of Company and to increase revenue with new projects on software development & Corporate Learning & Development solutions.
- Developing goals for the Sales Team and ensuring they are met.
- Research and identify customer prospects and target in Indian market and Middle East.
- Execute the enterprise & corporate sales strategy set by the management.
- Responsible for business development on existing software product Sales CRM & Custom software development.
- Responsible for business development on existing Learning & Development product -Online courses for corporates, ILT, VILT & Blended Learning Programs.
- Manage all steps in the sales pipeline including demos, proposals, securing required contract paperwork, and coordinating with the operations team to drive ongoing sucess and adoption.
- Attending conferences, meetings, and industry events. Developing quotes and proposals for clients.

BS SOFTWARES - SAAS, ERP, HRM & Custom Software Development Sales
BRANDSCREEN WEB - Website, Ecommerce Development & Digital marketing
BRANDSCREEN ADS - Advertising, Branding, Merchandising & PR
BRANDSCREEN STUDIO PRODUCTION - Creatve Designs & Video Ads,
Corporate Ads

Locations - Jharkhand, Bihar, Odissa, West Bengal, Bangalore, Noida, Delhi, Mumbai. Jan 2012 - March 2022

Engaged as Entrepreneur with vast exposure in various Domains -

Software & Technology, Digital Marketing, Creative, Branding & PR, Advertising and Visual & Retails Merchandizing.

Mostly worked for SME & Corporates.

BS Softwares

SAAS | CRM | Loyalty Software | Digital Coupon | Digital QR Menu ERP - Billing Software | Payroll & Attendance Management Software AR(Augmented Realty) - Hotel Menu | Real Estate

- Software development isince 2012 and explored business opportunities from government sector, local market & international market.
- Experience in selling Softwares to Corporate, SME, Retails chain, Channel selling.
- Explored & Developed new markets in Tier- II, Tier- III Cities in India.
- International exposure in acquiring new clients for custom developmet.
- Good knowledge of Plex server hosting for SAAS based softwares.
- In House Team for Sofware design & development with Experience Sales Team.
- Deep knowledge for creation, Implementation & Execution for development & sales strategies..
- Build market with 200+ customers which includes selling of in house softwares and custom developd softwares.
- Responsible for Direct selling as well as Team Management, and ensure for the porductivity & efficiency with meeting revenue profits.

Brandscreen Web

- Started Website designing & development in 2014 and delivered quality sites to indian & international customers.
- In House Team for Website designing & development.
- Developed 100+ Websites & ecommerce sites and maintained profitibility for the business.

Brandscreen Ads & Creative Studio

- Started Advertising & Creative designing business in 2012 and explored business opportunities from local market to international market.
- Helped customers with more visibility & profitablity of their business by Advertisement services with Outdoor & Indoor advertisement products.
- Enhanced the business with Branding solutions to SME & Corporates in different cities.
- Increased product & services portfolio with -
 - **Digital Ads Screens** all over Jharkhand & Odissa. 50+ Indoor LED screens, installed in restaurants, Hospital, Nursing homes, Malls, Cinema halls. Acquired many Large & small corporate clients along with local customers.
 - **Outdoor Digital Van Advertisement** in Eastern india. 6+ Ad vans with major clients in corporate like Banking, FMCG, FMCD.
- Got recognizition from many corporates for completing branding projects with disciplinary manner along with their brand guidelines.
- Creative Designing Studio with in house team of highly experienced graphic designers & AD video developers.
- Created Out of Box Brand identity for many clients along with 500+ logo designs. Note - Our price range for logo designing was from 3000/- to 25000/-. We delivered quality designs with standard brand guidelines for indian & international clients.
- Developed 500+ Video ADS for Cinema hall commercials and social media promotions.
- Done makeover of many Retail showrooms with Visual designing & merchandising.

HDFC BANK LTD.

Retail Banking | Branch Banking | Forex Trade

Sales Manager (Direct, Indirect & Channel Sales)

Nov 2007 to Nov 2011 | Jharkhand & Odissa

- Responsibilities include new acquisition of HNI clients and providing banking services.
- Responsibilities include focusing on Emerging Enterprises group such as CC/TL/BG,LC, Credit assessment and analysis, including business financial and management profiling. Evaluate credit requirements of potential customers.
- Responsibilities include sourcing of Retail Asset products i.e Personal loan, Business loan, LAP, from Team in Jharkhand & Odissa location..
- Maintaining Login/Disbursment TAT, Branch operations & Audit compliance.
- Developing goals for the Sales Team and ensuring they are met.
- Responsibilities include sourcing of Asset business through DSA, DST and Branch level.
- Responsibility include focusing on banking product as well i.e CASA,FD, NRI BUSINESS, FOREX TRADE, INVESTMENTS.
- Business plaining & forecasting in the assigned territory with new business ideas. Developing corporate Tie-ups to increase Retail assets business. Conducting Road shows & other marketing activities.
- Providing Product & Business Training to Sales Team and DSA.
- Co-ordinating with Operation unit / Risk unit / Credit unit for smooth work in sales process.

BAJAJ ALLIANZ LIFE INSURANCE CO. LTD..

Agency Channel - Life Insurance

Sales Manager

Feb 2007 to July 2011 | Jamshedpur

- Recruitment of insurance advisors for sales of life insurance products.
- Providing insurance training to advisors and encouraging them to undergo training program frequently.
- Achiving team targets by selling insurance products and motivating them.
- Conducting road shows and activities in housing societies to create awareness about life insurance.

ICICI BANK LTD.

Retail Assets - Loans

Business Channel Manager

March 2004 to Jan 2007 | Jharkhand - Jamshedpur

- Responsibilities include development of Channel in assigned territory for selling of personal loans, business loan products. Business planning & forecasting in the assigned territory.
- Recruitment and training of Sales team direct & indirect both. Appointing new DSAs in jamshedpur and near by areas.
- Organizing Various activities for DSA so to meet targets.
- Developing goals for the Sales Team and ensuring they are met.

EUREKA FORBES LTD.

Direct Sales - Vaccum Cleaner & Aqua Guard

Sales Executive

Aug 2003 to Feb 2004 | Jharkhand - Jamshedpur

- Started Sales carrer with Eureka forbes and sold Highest number of Industrial vaccum cleaner in 2nd month in Jharkhand region.
- Direct selling of Vaccum cleaner & aqua guard cross sell in residential areas.

IT SKILLS

Microsoft office, Bloomr CRM.

Adode Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator.

PERSONALITY TRAITS

- Strong Motivational Skills. Good Communication Skills.
- Remarkable analytical, logical skills
- Ability to give the best result in pressure situations.
- Project management & collaboration skills.
- Business Intelligence, market research and strategic analysis skills.

EDUCATION

Diploma in Sales Management form INSTITUTE OF SALE TRAINING (Jamshedpur) Year 2003

Graduation in Arts Year 2006

Intermediate in Arts Year 2003

Matriculation from CBSE Year 2001

SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

Initative & Drive

Planning

Process & Organizing skills

Interpersonal & Team Relationship

Creativity

Operations & Time Management

Communication & Leadership skills

PERSONAL DETAIL

Name : Harprit Singh

Father Name : Late Manjeet Singh

Nationality : Indian

Date of Birth : 07 July 1983

Religion : Sikh

Marital Status : Married

Present CTC : 14 Lac

Expected CTC : 18 - 22 lac

Preferred Location: Mumbai

Language Known: Punjabi, Hindi, English

LinkedIn : https://www.linkedin.com/in/harprit-singh-460780212/

0

CONTACT DETAIL

Address:

Flat no. 1001, Building no. 7, DB Ozone, Nr. Thakur Mall, Dahisar East, Mumbai - 400068

+91 8779651579 | +91 9973224021 smilehpsingh@gmail.com | harprit@goalseek.in

Date:

Place : Mumbai Signature :